Raphael Amponsah

Assistant Lecturer

Contact

Address

P. O. Box 527 Accra, Takoradi

Phone

(+233) 0503422990

E-mail

raamponsah@gimpa.edu.gh

Skills

Team Leadership & Direction

Excellent

Enterprise Resource Planning

Excellent

Policy & Procedure Planning

Excellent

Budget coordination

Excellent

Data Analysis

Excellent

Python | JavaScript

Very Good

PHP

Very Good

Laravel

An academic poised on delivery well-balanced lectures and passionate about imparting knowledge to those he teaches. Has deep interest in contemporary learning technologies and has gained experience in the area of research and teaching over the past years. A team-player and a person has a knack for excellence in delivery of results.

Work History

2016-01 -Current

Assistant Lecturer

Ghana Institute of Management and Public Administration, GIMPA, Achimota

- Wrote and modernised Management Information Systems, Business Intelligence, E-Business, IT Project Management course materials, including syllabi, assignments and exams
- Taught diverse student population by employing various learning styles and abilities
- Instructed students using lectures, discussions and demonstrations in E-Business
- Developed and proctored exams to properly gauge information retention and student performance
- Tracked student assignments, attendance and test scores and entered into online database to provide real-time progress monitoring
- Planned lectures based on targeted learning outcomes as assigned by organisational leadership
- Utilised instructional technologies in course delivery for both in-class and online instruction to engage and educate students

2016-02 -2019-02

Administrator

Spark Secretarial And IT Services, Accra, Greater Accra

- Assessed personnel performance and implemented incentives and team-building events to boost morale
- Assisted in decision-making procedures by creating daily reports to advise business on corrective actions and process improvements
- Adapted to workflow changes and implemented

Very Good React, React Native, Express Excellent MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB (NoSQL), Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Excellent **NodeJs** Excellent Software Microsoft Word Excellent Microsoft Excel Very Good

marketing initiatives

Maximized branding outreach by facilitating

obstacles

 Oversaw budget and tracked expenses against plans

continuous process improvements to overcome

- Entered and maintained departmental records into company database using Excel, Quickbooks and self-developed ledger software
- Computerized office activities, maintained customer communications and tracked records through delivery
- Made decisions affecting daily operations such as overseeing purchasing and inventory management
- Codified office structures and processes to promote teamwork and performance
- Maintained accurate, current and compliant financial records by monitoring and addressing variances

Personal Administrative Assistant

University Of Ghana, Legon

- Responded to emails and other correspondence to facilitate communication and enhance business processes
- Allocated executive tasks and managed complex calendars and administrative functions
- Composed internal memos and external correspondence for senior management and reviewed all documentation to eliminate errors
- Produced highly accurate internal and external letters and memoranda
- Recorded expenses and maintained accounting records in Excel
- Worked with supervisors and management to maintain status reports and update information for students projects
- Created and updated physical records and digital files to maintain current, accurate and compliant documentation

2011-08 -2014-08

Microsoft Project

Microsoft Publisher

Microsoft Powerpoint

Excellent

Excellent

Excellent

Microsoft Visio

Excellent

Quickbooks

Very Good

Adobe Photoshop

Excellent

Adobe Illustrator

Excellent

2011-08 -Teaching and Research Assistant

A 1				
$\Lambda \alpha \alpha$	\sim	n n		\sim
Ado			-	
, , ,				9, .

Excellent

Adobe AfterEffects

Very Good

2014-06

University of Ghana, Accra

- Supported instructor with test administration, curriculum development and assignment grading
- Supported student learning objectives through personalised and small group assistance to support classroom instruction
- Encouraged dynamic and pleasant educational environment by promoting both gentle discipline among peers and students
- Assisted teachers with supervision and care of group of 600 students
- Maintained schedule of support services and attended all sessions especially chemistry practicals

2010-06 -2010-09

Quality Control Intern

West African Mills Company, WAMCO

- Specified quality requirements of raw materials with suppliers
- Collected production samples regularly and performed detailed quality inspections
- Estimated financial requirements of new projects
- Determined quality department standards, practices and procedures

Education

2020-current

PHD Student, University of Ghana,

2014-08 -2016-06 MPhil. Management Information Systems

Ghana Institute Of Management And Public

Dissertation: Explicating user-centered security from the perspective of perceived affordance

2007-08 -2011-05

Bachelor of Science: Chemistry

University Of Ghana - Legon, Accra

 Dissertation: The Production of Biodegradable Plastic from Cassava Starch for Consumer Packaging by Raphael Amponsah, Johnson K. Efavi, Nana Yaw Samuel, Walter Affo; (Journal of Ghana Science Association, 2012)

2003-09 - **Science**

Scholarly Publications

A semiotic study of lingua-culture of digital paralanguages

R Amponsah, R Boateng, EA Kolog, AMCIS 2021

COVID-19 Pandemic: How can the Lessons Learnt Contribute to the Digital Transformation of Schools of Tomorrow?

EA Kolog, SB Egala, R Amponsah, SNO Devine, E Sutinen
International Journal of Technology Enhanced Learning

The Production of Biodegradable Plastic from Cassava Starch for Consumer

Packaging

Raphael Amponsah, Johnson K. Efavi, Nana Yaw Samuel, Walter Affo;

Journal of Ghana Science Association, 2012

Web Projects

- Ghana College of Pharmacists Council Website: http://www.gcpharm.edu.gh
- Energy Always Foundation: https://www.efghana.org/
- Prestige Décor: http://www.prestige-decor.com/
- Presbyterian Website: http://pcgchristchurch.org/
- Upcoming Works Our Lady of Apostles Catholic Church Website A SAAS typical Ghanaian church management system

Programs Organised and Managed

 Successfully led and creatively organised "Lovetail 2019 and "2020 a musical concert to raise an amount of GHS70,000.00 for Our Lady of Apostles Catholic

Church, Madina without touching internal church coffers. This event drew about 600 to 800 people. All triple constraints of the project was met. This event was deemed successful, thus have been given the nod to organise another in 2021

 Upcoming Drama-fest dubbed "MUSA" written by myself (Raphael Amponsah) which would be acted next year

Certifications

2016-08	MPhil. Management Information Systems
2013-06	Software Development (STDIO Ghana-University of Florida)
2011-06	Chemistry Students Association-University of Ghana
2013-06	Software Development (STDIO Ghana-University of Florida)
2013-04	April 2013 International English Language Testing System
2011-05	Certificate of Honor as the Chief Editor-Chemistry
2008-02	Certificate of Honor as the Chief Editor
2006-07	Secondary Certificate Examination West African Senior University of Ghana (WASSCE)
2003-01	Tour Operators Ghana (TOUGHA) Certificate (As part of the TOUGHA competition)
2003-11	Basic Education Certificate Examination (B.E.C.E)

Interests

Photography

Encountering New people

Writing Poems

Reading a lot of articles

Playing Video Games

Hobbies

Hove writing poems and drawing

References

- Mr. Clement Ansah
 Cluster Manager
 Southern Central
 Consolidated Bank Ghana (CBG)
 clement.ansah@cbg.com.gh
 +233 244 591 473
- Prof. Gamel O. Wiredu
 Snr. Lecturer, School of Technology
 Head, Quality Assurance, GIMPA
 P. O. Box AH50, Accra
 Tel: +233 207 800 428
 gwiredu@gimpa.edu.gh
- Rev. Fr. Wilmer S. Cacao, SMA
 Assistant Parish Priest
 Queen of Peace Catholic Church
 Madina, Accra
 jhaimlerwilmersiribancacao@gmail.com
 0550122423